六  七  八
Six, seven, eight.
干嘛一大早就跟碧昂斯似的
Why you are Beyonce this morning?
你参加了学校的舞蹈社团吗
You've got a school dance corner?
不是  阿什莉教了我一些啦啦队的舞步
No. Ashley gave me some of her cheer routine.
她在校队待了两年
She's been on the J.V. for two years,
她想让我也试试加入
and she wants me to try out for the squad.
啦啦队
Cheerleading?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
你是谁  你把我女儿弄哪去了
Who are you and what have you done with my daughter?
啦啦队有什么不好的吗
What's wrong with cheerleading?
没  没什么  只是
No, no, nothing's-- nothing's...
我只是  没想到你会想成为其中一员
I'm just--I didn't know you... wanted to be one.
我也没想到
Me either.
但我看了阿什莉排练  挺有意思的
But I watched Ashley practice, and it looks like fun.
而且我的升学辅导员  雪弗女士说
And my college counselor, Ms. Schaefer,
我需要丰富一下我的课外活动
said I need to consider diversifying my activities.
我觉得我颇具天赋
I figure I'm a natural
因为我整天为你摇旗呐喊
'cause I root for you all the time.
我得走了
Oh, I gotta go.
-爱你  -玩的开心点
- Love you. - Have fun.
五六七八
Five. Six. Seven. Eight.
啦啦队
Cheerleading?
怎么了
So?
-谁...  -还记得你以前想打曲棍球吗
- Who... - Ah. The time you wanted to play hockey
因为学校里的风云人物都玩那个
because all the cool guys in school were playing it?
-没错  但我可没加入球队  -拉倒吧
- Yeah, but I didn't join the team. - Well, no,
还不是因为你一上场就磕掉两颗牙
because you knocked out two teeth at the first practice.
宝贝
Darling...
让阿丽克西斯自己去领悟这些吧  好吗
let Alexis figure this out on her own, hmm?
那你上个礼拜干嘛不让我
This coming from the woman who just last week told me
在太空梭上预约位置
not to reserve a seat on the space shuttle?
好吧  这个可以从长计议
Oh. Well, we have to rethink that.
-真的  -嗯
- Really?  - Mm-hmm.
受害人为女性  接近30岁  身份不明
Vic's a female, late 20s, no I.D.
天刚亮的时候被一个晨练者
She was found hanging from the monkey bars
发现吊在攀架上
by a jogger just after dawn.
那是蜂蜜吗
Is that honey?
从气味上判断  是焦糖酱
From the smell of it, I'd say it's caramel sauce.
但还得进一步测试  而不是"尝"试
But I'll be testing, not tasting.
焦糖酱
Caramel sauce?
也许凶手喜欢甜食
Maybe our killer has a sweet tooth.
从她暴露的衣着来看
Given her state of undress,
我想凶手更像是有某种性癖好
I'd say it's more likely he had a sexual fetish.
没错  我可以接受巧克力
Yeah, I can do the chocolate,
甚至是奶油抹在比基尼部位
I'll even do the whipped cream bikini,
但是焦糖
but caramel?
我喜欢滑溜溜  不要黏糊糊
I prefer slippery to sticky.
她知道我们能听见她的话吗
Does she know we can hear her?
性趣手铐  还是订做的
Bondage cuffs, custom made?
看来凶手喜欢在公共场合玩这个
Looks like our killer liked public play.
你从哪儿看出
How can you tell the difference
那是订做的还是一般的
between custom and regular?
这种皮革大批量生产成本太高
The leather is too high quality to be mass-produced,
而且这是手工缝制的
and it's hand-stitched.
不  我是说  "你"是怎么看出来的
No, I mean, how can you tell the difference?
-死亡时间?  -从尸体温度判断
- So time of death?  - From body temperature,
应该是在昨晚10点到11点之间
I'd say between 10:00 and 11:00 last night.
但我确定她不是在这里遇害的
But I'm pretty sure she was not killed here.
从尸体青紫程度来看
Based on lividity,
尸体在遇害地点停留了数小时
she spent several hours in the fetal position after she died,
然后几小时前才被吊在这里
and then was hung here a few hours ago.
淤血说明她是窒息而死
Petechial hemorrhaging suggests she was suffocated.
另外还有这些
And then there's these.
-她被绑过吗  -看上去是的
- Was she restrained?  - Looks like it.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
犯罪现场没有留下任何挣扎痕迹
Crime scene's negative for any signs of a struggle.
发现了一些不完整的鞋印
Found about a dozen partial shoe impressions,
但地面太硬没办法取样
but the ground's too cold to get any imprints.
但是  我们发现了这个
But... we did find this.
轮子痕迹  间距大约18英寸
Wheel marks, about 18 inches apart.
可拖式行李箱吗
Rolling suitcase?
从痕迹的深度来看
And judging by the depth of the tracks,
箱子里装的东西很重
I'd say it was carrying something heavy.
我估计  大约105磅
I'm guessing around, uh, 105 pounds.
那么  他在别的地方杀了她然后移尸此处
So he killed her elsewhere and then brought her here.
这意味着凶杀现场可能是任何地方
Yeah, which means the crime scene could be anywhere.
这从心理学上说不通啊
The psychology doesn't make any sense.
犯罪现场被精心布置过了
The crime scene was pretty elaborately staged,
这说明
which seems to suggest
凶手是早有预谋的
a significant amount of premeditation.
但从窒息杀人这种方法本身来说
But the murder itself-- suffocation--
通常意味着冲动型凶杀
might indicate a crime of passion.
那家伙在她身上抹了焦糖
Guy covered her in caramel.
你真觉得这凶手还有逻辑可言吗
Do you really think we're gonna find a logical explanation?
纽约提供订做服务的
Only a handful of bondage shops
性趣用品商店屈指可数
in the city do custom work.
把这些手铐的照片散出去
So let's take photos of those cuffs, send it out,
看有没有人能认出是哪里做的
see if anyone can I.D. where it came from.
屈指可数
"Only a handful of shops"?
你到底还有多少事我不知道的
Okay, what aren't you telling me?
太多了  卡塞尔  一言难尽呐
So much, Castle. So very, very much.
看这种东西时你在我脖子旁喘气
It's a little creepy doing this
让我直起鸡皮疙瘩
with you breathing on my neck.
不好意思  我也想自己看自己的
Oh, sorry, bro. I mean, I'd do it on mine,
但是情报部门会查浏览记录  所以
but I.A. checks browser history, so...
很好  多谢了
Great. Thanks.
那玩意是干嘛的
What does that thing do?
看起来像是土豆削皮器
Looks like a potato peeler.
哦  这也太恶心了
Yeah. Oh, that is nasty.
而且在12个州都是违法的
And illegal in 12 states.
你说的没错  的确很奇怪
Yeah, you're right. That is weird.
-好的  谢谢  -什么很奇怪
- Okay. Thank you.  - What's weird?
蕾妮做了检验
Lanie ran a sart kit.
没有任何性侵犯或者性行为的迹象
There's no signs of sexual assault or activity.
这案子具备了一切性犯罪的特征
This has all the makings of a sex crime,
但却与性无关
but there's no sex involved.
也许这变态是个禁欲主义者呢
Well, maybe our psychopath believes in abstinence.
我看更可能是性无能吧
It's more likely he has a performance problem.
而且死者身份不明
And there's no I.D.,
她的指纹也不在系统数据库里
her fingerprints aren't in the system.
这种姿势怎么摆出来的
How do you even get in that position?
我也不知道  但你可以和
I don't know, but you should try that with your,
你的宝贝女朋友试下  说实在的
uh, girlfriend, honey milk. As a matter of fact,
我现在就要去给你买个这玩意
I think I'm gonna buy this for you right now.
神呐  这姿势到底怎么摆出来的
Oh, jeez. How do you even get in that position?
我就说吧  根本没可能
Right? It's not even possible.
还是有可能的
Oh, it's possible.
-有什么进展吗  -还没有
- Anything on the canvass?  - Nothing yet.
失踪人口登记也没有任何消息
And nothing back from missing persons.
不过鉴于案件是昨晚刚发生的
Given that it just happened last night,
所以可能要再等几天才会有人报案
it's most likely not gonna be reported for a couple of days.
那手铐呢
What about the cuffs?
我们在曼哈顿地区找到了7家店铺
We found seven shops in Manhattan
可以提供性趣性虐用品订做服务
that make custom bondage gear.
而且我们在等待反馈的同时
And while we're waiting to hear back,
还要给莱恩的假想女友买个小礼物
we're gonna buy a gift for Ryan's imaginary girlfriend.
就是  我们什么时候能见见你的珍妮
Oh, yeah. When are we gonna meet that Jenny?
等时机差不多了  我自然会带她过来
When the time is right, I'll bring her around.
我可不想她被你们吓跑了
I don't want you guys scaring her off.
噢  她来电话了
Oh, there she is now.
-好吧  我瞎猜的  -你好  莱恩警探
- Ugh, I don't know. - Hello. Detective Kevin Ryan.
你们俩就别拿他开涮了
You guys, give him a break.
换我也不会带男朋友来这的
I wouldn't bring my boyfriend around here either.
男朋友  我错过了什么好戏吗
Boyfriend? Did I miss something?
"锁爱"商店的老板巴利打电话来说
So that was Barry from the love shackle.
那些手铐可能是他们店里的
He says the cuff might be theirs,
但他必须亲自查看一下才能确定
but he'd have to examine 'em up close to know for sure.
嗯  那就把证物拿给他们看
Well, then have evidence pull them
告诉他们我也会过去
and tell them I'm coming.
噢  性用品店之旅
Oh, a field trip to a sex store.
我爱死这单案子了
I love this case.
看他鞍前马后的样子
Look at him following her.
谁要挨鞭子  我还是他
Who's whipped, huh, me or him?
你  兄弟  认命吧
You, bro, hands down.
咱们既然来了
You know, while we're here,
就应该买点东西
we should really pick up something
给你那位假想男友
for that new imaginary boyfriend of yours.
喔  这个合他口味吗
Oh, this his speed?
不
No.
但如果你再啰嗦
But if you keep talking,
我就让你尝尝这个
I'll put you in one of these.
二位好  有什么特殊需要吗
Hey, guys. Looking for something special?
-有  -没有
- Yes! - No!
才刚开始尝试  是吧
Just gettin' started, huh?
来我们这儿的很多都是第一次
Yeah, we get a lot of first timers.
我们从性癖好最基本的内容开始
We carry everything from bondage 101
一直到高阶用品应有尽有
all the way up to the more advanced stuff
爽到家的专业行头
for your pleasure PhD.
但如果你们只是想浅尝辄止的话
But if you're just looking to dip your toe in the water,
这个小玩意是最佳选择
these little guys are best sellers.
-想试试不  -不用了
- Want to give 'em a try? - No, thanks.
我自己已经有一副了
I've already got a pair of my own.
接缝处是双圈交叉法缝制
Double cross lap stitch on the seam.
没错  这肯定是出自我手
Yeah, this is definitely one of mine.
能告诉我们是谁要求订做的吗
Can you tell us who ordered them?
可以  我记得那孩子
Yeah, I remember this kid.
很清纯的样子
Very vanilla.
印证了那句话  看上去越正常的
Then again, it's always the normal-looking ones
私底下越疯狂  对吧
that end up being the most freaky, right?
你有他的姓名或者地址吗
Do you have a name or a billing address?
有  这副手铐是6个月前买的
Yeah. The cuffs were purchased six months ago
付款人是泰勒·本顿
by a Tyler Benton.
他特地为他女友订做的
He had 'em specially made for his girlfriend.
那女孩也很漂亮
Cute girl, too.
-你还记得她吗  -是啊  褐色头发  20多岁
- You remember her? - Yeah, brunette, mid-20s,
问了不少问题
asked a lot of questions.
她不会就是这个人吧
Did she by any chance look like this?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
我们得和泰勒·本顿谈谈
We need to talk to Tyler Benton
弄清楚他昨晚做了些什么
and find out what he was doing last night.
我猜就是杀女朋友吧
My guess is killing his girlfriend.
这就是杰西卡
That's Jessica.
杰西卡·马戈利斯  我的女友
Jessica Margolis-- My girlfriend.
下周就是我们一周年纪念了
Next week was our one-year anniversary.
我本打算求婚的
I was going to propose.
你昨晚在哪  本顿先生
Where were you last night, Mr. Benton?
在医院  我是实习医生
At the hospital. I'm a first year.
昨天值的是24小时的班
I was working a 24-hour shift.
你可以问带我的主治医生
You can ask my attending.
你见过这个吗
Have you ever seen these before?
见过  我几个月前买给杰西卡的  怎么了
Yeah, I-I bought them for Jessica a few months ago. Why?
尸体被这个吊在公园后被发现了
She was found hanging by them in the park.
-你们喜欢这样玩吗  -什么
- You guys like to play? - What?
不  我们根本就没用过这些
No. We never even used them.
这些  这些只不过是个玩笑而已
They were--they were just supposed to be a joke.
-因为她的研究  -研究
- Because of her research.  - Research?
我只是想尽量支持她
I tried to be supportive,
但我本该阻止她的
but I should've stopped her.
我应该劝她去研究别的课题
I should've pushed her to study something else.
她研究的课题是什么
What was she studying?
性虐群体生态学
The sociology of sexual bondage and domination.
她花了几个月的时间和那些人相处
She spent months meeting people in that world,
试着去弄懂是什么令他们神魂颠倒
trying to understand what made them tick.
而他们却因此杀了她
And they killed her for it.
你平时把这些手铐收在哪里
And where did you keep these cuffs?
我不  我不知道
I don't--I don't know.
我猜是在她那里吧  她室友可能知道
At her place, I guess. Her roommate probably knows.
她们两人平时形影不离的
The two of them were, like, attached at the hip.
杰西卡和我
Jessica and I
从刚入学开始就是室友了
have been roommates since freshman year.
我们已在一起住了很久  情同姐妹
We've lived together so long, we're practically sisters.
泰勒说你可能知道
Tyler said that you might know
她把他送的手铐收在了什么地方
where she kept the cuffs he gave her.
她刚拿到手时给我看过
Oh, she showed them to me when she got them,
但从那以后我再也没看见过
but I never saw them after that.
那你最后一次见到杰西卡是什么时候
And when was the last time that you saw Jessica?
昨天早上
Yesterday morning.
那关于她的研究呢
What about her research?
她有没有和你说过去过什么地方
Did she ever talk to you about where she went,
还有接触了什么人
uh, the people involved?
没有  她对于那些很保密
No, she pretty much kept all that to herself.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
失陪了
Excuse me.
床没有人躺过
So the bed hasn't been slept in.
也没有任何挣扎的痕迹
There's no signs of a struggle.
-手机和钱包呢  -都没有
- Cell phone, purse? - Nada.
这说明她是
Which means she was
在别的地方遇害的
somewhere else when she was killed.
好了  跟踪她的手机号码
Okay, let's put a trace on her cell phone.
如果她有卫星定位装置就好办了
If she has a GPS locator, we might get lucky.
知道了
All right.
杰西卡有没有提过昨晚她要去哪儿
Did Jessica ever mention where she was going to be last night?
没有  我10点左右回来的
No. I-I got in at around 10:00.
看上去她没有回来过
It didn't look like she had been home.
因为泰勒在医院值班
Since Tyler was on call, I...
我就以为她是在学校通宵
I assumed she was up at the university
写论文
working on her thesis.
我也希望能帮到你  探长
I wish I could help you, detective.
她有时确实忙到很晚
Sometimes she'd work late,
但她昨晚不在这里
but she wasn't here last night.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
我昨晚改试卷一直到11点才走
I was here till 11:00 grading papers.
要是她在我一定会看见的
I would've seen her.
作为她的导师  你对她
As her advisor, how much would you know
调查的那些人有多少了解呢
about the people that she was researching?
她有很长一段时间都和一个名叫
She was spending a lot of time with a dominatrix
"毒液女王"的施虐女郎在一起
named Mistress Venom.
"毒液女王"
Mistress Venom?
听起来像是《阁楼》[男性杂志]讨论版
Sounds more like
而不是什么博士课程
"Penthouse Forum" than PhD.
卡塞尔先生  研究性相关领域的人
Mr. Castle, people who study sex-related fields
总是被学术界嘲笑
are often derided within academia.
杰西卡只是不想被他们的狭隘之见
Jessica was determined not to be held hostage
所阻挠而已
by their little minds.
"毒液"是杰西卡那方面的引荐人
Venom was Jessica's guide to that world.
如果你想了解更多关于
If you want to know more about
杰西卡所研究的人
the people Jessica was studying,
你得去问问"毒液"
You'll have to ask Venom.
凯莉  这是贝克特探长
Kelly, this is detective Beckett
还有理查德·卡塞尔
and Richard Castle.
他们要查看下杰西卡的研究资料
They need to see Jessica's research.
她一直锁着笔记吗
She kept her notes locked up?
她是凯勒曼奖学金的最终竞争者之一
She was a finalist for the Kellerman fellowship.
很显然
You know,
与同院系的人竞争
when you're competing against other people in the department,
笔记随处乱摆
the last thing you want to do is
可不是什么好主意
leave your notes lying around.
看起来你们经常熬夜
Well, it looks like a lot of late nights.
当泰勒要值班时
When Tyler was on shift,
她就会开通宵  然后乘他
she'd just pull an all-nighter and go visit
休息的时候去看他
him on his breaks.
凯莉  你知道他们找到她时什么情况不
Kelly, did you hear how they found her?
马特
Matt--
只穿着内衣被吊在游戏区的攀爬架上
Tied to the monkey bars on a playground in her underwear?
马特  这是贝克特探长
Matt, um, this is detective Beckett.
她是来调查杰西卡的案件的
She's here investigating Jessica's death.
马特  杰西和我
Matt, Jess and I
是同时开始攻读博士课程的
all started the PhD program at the same time.
可以看出你们关系"不错"
I can tell you were close.
-抱歉  我只是  -凯莉
- I'm sorry. It's just... - Kelly,
杰西卡在院系里有没有什么仇人
did Jessica have any enemies in the department?
或是不能和睦相处的人
Anyone in school that she didn't get along with?
就算我们为同一奖学金竞争
Just because we were competing for the same fellowship
也不能说明我们相处不好吧
doesn't mean that we weren't civil.
不是每个人都那么友好的  过去几周内
Not everyone was civil. In the last few weeks,
杰西卡在她办公室里
Jessica was getting these phone calls
接到好几个电话
on her office line.
什么样的电话
What kind of calls?
喘气  呻吟
Um, heavy breathing, moaning.
听完恨不得用消毒液洗澡
Made you want to take a hand sanitizer shower.
研究生玩这套似乎略显不成熟
Seems a little immature for grad students.
听着  我研究的是
Look, I'm studying the impact
接收艾滋病患对市区门诊的影响
of AIDS treatments in inner-city clinics.
凯莉研究如何克服晋升歧视等无形障碍问题
Kelly's is about overcoming the glass ceiling.
而杰西卡却在观察一个性虐女郎
And Jessica was watching a dominatrix
把细高的鞋跟踩入一个窝囊废的胸膛
dig her stiletto into some loser's chest.
她接到那种电话一点也不奇怪
She was bound to get some grief for it. Ah.
关于"毒液"施虐过程的笔记太详细了
Jessica's notes on Venom's sessions are pretty detailed.
简直就像把他们当实验鼠一样研究
She studied these guys like lab rats.
但她只用绰号来标记他们  比如人妖
But she only identifies them by nickname--"Ladyboy,"
别针坐垫男  还有惊慌兔
"Pin cushion" and "Scared bunny."
如果他们不知道杰西卡是在做研究
You know, if they didn't know what Jessica was doing,
然而其中有人发现了
and one of them found out...
害怕被暴露是很强的杀人动机
Fear of exposure would be a strong motive to kill.
真搞不懂她为什么迷上这个
I wonder what attracted her to all this.
根据她论文的开题报告
Well, according to her thesis proposal,
她是在亲眼目睹一段不正常性关系后
she became interested in s&m after witnessing
才对性虐产生兴趣的
a dysfunctional relationship up close.
很明显  她的论文
Apparently her dissertation
对比了"地牢"里公然的控制欲
compares the overt expressions of dominance in the dungeon
和现实世界隐晦的控制欲
to more subtle expressions in real-world relationships...
比如说对方向盘的控制
Like who drives.
你肯让我开车我自然会开
Hey, I would drive if you would let me.
想的挺好  说出来怎么变味儿了
That actually didn't prove my point like I thought it would.
里面说了"毒液女王"
You know, it says here that Mistress Venom
在"地牢巷"的某个性虐俱乐部工作
works in a bondage club somewhere in dungeon alley,
但没指明是哪个
but it doesn't say which one.
"地牢巷"
Dungeon alley.
在切尔西区和市中心区之间
It's an area between chelsea and midtown.
那里都是些特殊性癖好俱乐部
There's a whole slew of fetish clubs there.
我当然知道"地牢巷"在哪儿
Yes, I know where dungeon alley is.
我很奇怪你怎么会知道呢
I want to know... how do you know?
突击检查了一些俱乐部
Vice raided a few of them
想找些证据关闭他们
looking for a reason to shut them down.
但因为没有性交易
But since there's no sexual contact
而且那些行为都你情我愿
and the acts are all consensual,
所以他们完全合法
it was all perfectly legal.
知道吗  你应该去兼职
Hmm. You know, you should moonlight.
说实话  你会发大财的
Seriously, you would make a fortune.
得了吧  难道你没想过
Come on. Haven't you ever wanted to do...
用你的手铐做些其他事
something with your handcuffs
而不是逮捕罪犯
other than arrest criminals?
没想过
No.
但的确有件激情的
But there is one hot...
狂野的
wild...
出格的事情我喜欢做
kinky thing that I do like doing.
就是将凶手绳之以法
Putting killers behind bars.
瞧见没  你已经懂得戏弄人了  已经上道了
See? You're already a tease. You're halfway there.
我们试着追踪那些
Hey, we tried to trace the creepy calls
打到杰西卡办公室的变态电话
that Jessica was getting at her office.
但因为它们都是
But since they were routed
由学校总线转入的
through the main switchboard at the college,
所以无法查到来源
there's no way to determine their source.
手机情况怎样
What about the cell phone?
她遇害当天
The day she died,
曾打给了医院里的男友
she placed a call to her boyfriend at the hospital,
也给办公室的语音信箱留了言
she placed a call to her voice mail at the office,
给"伊琳娜夫人的痛苦庄园"打了两个
and she placed two calls to "Lady Irena's house of pain".
"伊琳娜夫人的痛苦庄园"
"Lady Irena's house of pain"?
"毒液女王"应该在那工作
That must be where Mistress Venom works.
有地址没
Did you get an address?
有的  38大道的一栋办公楼
Yeah, an office building on 38th.
选址不错嘛  想吃饭后甜点的人相当方便啊
Oh, conveniently located for all your lunchtime spanking needs.
你们继续查看她的笔记
All right you guys look through her notes,
看看能不能查出
see if there's anything that's there
任何她客户的线索
that might implicate one of her clients.
而我和卡塞尔
Meanwhile, Castle and I will
去会会那个"毒液女王"
go and meet this Mistress Venom.
鞭子  女人还有谋杀
Whips, women and murder--
看来我今天撞大运了
Sounds like my lucky day.
很高兴你喜欢这个
I'm so glad you're excited by this.
你好  我是凯特
Hi, my name is Kate,
我男友是个相当坏的家伙
and my boyfriend has been a very bad boy.
是的  就是那么回事
Yes, that's right.
-他叫里奇  -你在干嘛
- His name's Ricky. - What are you doing?
其实  我一个朋友向我推荐"毒液女王"
Actually, a friend of mine recommended a Mistress Venom.
-打住  -她今天有空吗  下午四点
- Wait. - Is she available today? 4:00 P.M.?
可以  太好了  谢了
Sure, that's perfect. Thank you.
好吧  这很有趣
Okay, that's very funny.
赶紧打回去取消
Now call her back.
才不呢  卡塞尔
Unh-unh, Castle.
这是接近"毒液"的
This is the perfect way to get Venom
最佳方法
without tipping our hand.
怎么了  卡塞尔
What's the matter, Castle?
害怕角色扮演吗
You afraid of a little role play?
是哦  你最好快点闪
Yeah, you better run.
这里看起来像个律师事务所
This place looks like a law firm.
那你以为应该是什么样的
What'd you think it was gonna be?
到处都是酷刑轮和穿紧身内衣的女人吗
Torture wheels and women in corsets?
那当然了
Well, yeah.
都在里屋呢
That's in the back.
欢迎来到"伊琳娜夫人的痛苦庄园"
Welcome to "Lady Irena's house of pain".
有什么能效劳的
How can I serve you?
赶紧回答她吧
Well, answer her!
知道我为什么来这了吧
You see what I have to deal with?
我男友里奇在四点
My boyfriend Ricky has an appointment at 4:00 P.M.
和"毒液女王"有个预约
with Mistress Venom.
你要一起吗
Will you be joining him?
是的  我迫不及待地想看他的熊样儿
Oh, yes. I've been dying to watch him squirm.
"毒液女王"会很高兴有观众在场
Mistress Venom would be delighted to have an audience.
请跟我来
Follow me, please.
我们能堵住他的嘴吗
Do you think we could gag him?
记住  我的底限暗号是  苹果
Remember, my safe word is "apples."
你该把你的新男友带来
You should bring your new boyfriend here.
你是"毒液女王"吗
Mistress Venom?
"毒液女王"不能来
Mistress Venom is unavailable.
我是伊琳娜夫人
But I'm Lady Irena.
这家"地牢"是我开的
I own this dungeon.
我们能提供另外合适的"女王"
I'm sure we can find another dominatrix
来满足你们的需求
to suit your needs.
我想不行  我是贝克特探长
I'm afraid we can't. I'm detective Beckett.
我们正在调查一起谋杀案
I need to speak with her right now
我要立刻和她谈谈
concerning a murder investigation.
谁被杀了
Who was murdered?
杰西卡·马戈利斯
Jessica Margolis.
研究"毒液"施虐的一个博士生
The PhD student who was observing her sessions.
从来没人研究过她施虐
There was no one observing her sessions.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
当然  在我的"地牢"里隐私极为重要
Positive. Privacy is paramount in my dungeon.
你见过这个女孩吗
You've never seen this girl?
当然见过
Of course I've seen that girl.
她不是"毒液女王"的研究者
She wasn't observing Mistress Venom.
她就是"毒液女王"
She was Mistress Venom.
这就能解释她身上的痕迹了
This can explain the marks on her body.
杰西卡遇害之前肯定穿了
Jessica must have been
-这样的靴子  -类似这些酷刑靴
- wearing this before she died. - Like cruel shoes,
脱下后痕迹也可以持续几小时
these outfits can leave marks for hours after you wear them.
她昨天有三场施虐任务
She had three sessions yesterday.
7点半左右离开的
She left around 7:30.
你对杰西卡在你"地牢"里
You really had no idea that Jessica was conducting
-做社会调查一点也不知情吗  -不知道
- a sociological experiment out of your dungeon? - No.
大约六个月前  她来找我
She came to me about six months ago.
很快她就成为我这最火的施刑人之一
Quickly became one of my most requested doms.
她的客户中
Did Jessica have any clients
有没有对她神魂颠倒的
who were unusually obsessed with her?
当然 他们都入迷了
Of course. I mean, they all were.
她的客户都惟她是从
But her clients were submissive.
谋杀可是占支配地位的举动
Killing is an act of dominance.
你我都知道人不是那么简单的
You and I both know that people aren't that simple.
男人可能因为想被羞辱或拷问而来这里
Men might come here for humiliation and torture,
但有人因受虐过度而发飙
but it's easy to imagine that one of them
也是可能的
might have been pushed too far and lashed out.
如果她觉得自己有危险
If she was concerned for her safety,
肯定会和我说的
she would've told me.
-你有她的客户名单吗  -探长小姐
- Do you have a list of Jessica's clients? -Detective..
我们这提供的所有服务
All of the services that we provide here
都是完全合法的
are perfectly legal.
而服务的一部分就是
Now part of that service
保护客户的隐私
is protecting the privacy of our client.
守口如瓶可是客户花钱买的
I'm not about to betray the trust that
仅凭你的推测恕我不能开口
they've paid for because you have a hunch.
这不只是案情推测而已
Oh, I think it's more than just a hunch.
是嘛  我很抱歉
Well, gee, I'm sorry.
除非你有搜查令
Unless you have a court order,
否则我无能为力
my hands are tied, so to speak.
作为一个"女王"  你很通晓法律啊
You're pretty well-versed in law for a dominatrix.
别以貌取人
Don't let the leather fool you.
我以前可是律师事务所的合伙人
I used to be a partner at a law firm.
当你在会议室和审判庭里
When you dominate and manipulate men
控制和羞辱男人时
in every boardroom and courtroom that you're in,
一切都是那么天经地义
this just seemed like the natural progression.
这叫"血色女王"
It's called Mistress Red.
什么
Excuse me?
我的口红颜色
My lipstick.
我发现你一直盯着看
I noticed you couldn't stop staring.
抱歉  那色泽太迷人了
Sorry. It was just hypnotic.
不是气你  我气她
It's not you. It's her.
如果你现在很不爽
Well, if you're so upset,
我们可以找个人陪你玩原始游戏
we could find someone for you to go medieval on.
他怎么样
Like, uh, him perhaps.
她想袒护客户
She wants to protect her clients?
她手下的死活就不管了
What about her girls?
你是警察吗
Hey. You the cop?
我是贝克特探长
I'm detective Beckett.
我是"蓝宝石女王"  那件事是真的吗
I'm Mistress Sapphire. So it's true?
她死了
She's dead?
是的  我很抱歉
Yes. I'm sorry--
上周有件不寻常的事情
This weird thing happened last week
我觉得应该告诉你
I think you should know about.
跟她的客户有关系吗
With one of her clients?
差不多吧  有个第一次光顾的客人
Sort of. A first-time client came in
没几分钟就离开了
for a session, but he left just after a few minutes.
然后我发现她躲在更衣室里哭泣
I found her in the locker room, crying.
她告诉你原因没
Did she tell you why?
-没有  -你记得这个客户的特征吗
- No. - This client, do you remember anything about him?
这是一周前的事了  我也只看到他背面
It was a week ago, and I only saw him from behind.
不过他穿着类似医生的衬衫
But he was wearing one of those medical shirts.
实习医生穿的吗
Scrubs?
-是的  -我们想到一块了没
- Yes. - You thinking what I'm thinking?
杰西卡的男友发现了她的秘密身份
Jessica's boyfriend discovered her secret identity.
求婚戒指没送上  反而痛下杀手
And instead of proposing to her, he kills her.
杰西卡是我今生的挚爱
Jessica was the love of my life.
-我为何要伤害她  -因为她伤害了你
- Why would I want to hurt her? - Because she hurt you.
你说什么鬼话呢
What the hell are you talking about?
你自己也说过了  你想让她停止
You said so yourself. You wanted her to stop.
你想让她研究其他的东西
You were gonna make her study something else.
当你发现她不是在研究那个世界
It must have been a real shocker
她就是那个世界的一员时  你肯定
when you realized she wasn't just studying that world,
大吃一惊吧
she was living it.
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is this?
这太离谱了  你要告诉我这是真的吗
This is crazy. You're telling me this is real?
你说杰西卡就是其中一员
You're telling me Jessica was one of them?
你上周为什么去"地牢"
Why did you go to the dungeon last week?
-想当面戳穿她吗  -什么"地牢"
- Was it to confront her? - The dungeon?
我们有目击者看见你去了那里
We have a witness who saw you there.
这很好理解
It's completely understandable.
你爱的女人欺骗了你
The woman that you loved lied to you?
我可以想象你当时情绪如何失控
I could see how you could lose control
然后一时气愤痛下杀手
and go into a jealous rage.
接着处于惊慌之中
And then in a panic,
你决定以不寻常的方式弃尸
decide to stage the body in a manner so unusual,
让我们误以为这是性虐倾向的人干的
we'd naturally assume it was someone in the bondage world.
我从没去过什么"地牢"
I never went to a dungeon.
我也没痛下杀手  因为我根本不知道
There was no jealous rage because I didn't know!
我打算和她结婚的
I was going to marry her.
我们三天前才签了一份租约  准备同居
We just signed a lease to move in together three days ago.
如果我对她很恼火  为什么我还这么做
If I was so angry with her, why would I do that?
租约的事情是实话
He was telling the truth about the lease.
他们不仅一起签了租约
Not only did he and Jessica sign the lease,
而且还公证过
but it was also notarized.
那并不能说明他不是凶手
That doesn't mean he didn't do it.
可能是他故意让她签的  以此洗脱嫌疑
He could've had her sign to help his alibi.
也有可能她害怕他
Maybe she was afraid of him.
我一直在想  她在调查报告中提到的
I've been thinking-- the dysfunctional relationship
那段不正常的关系
she refers to in her research--
在一段文字里  她说到人物甲
There's a passage where she describes subject "A"
害怕告诉人物乙  她要离开了
as being afraid to tell subject "B" that she's leaving
因为乙已经疯狂地依赖纠缠她
because he's become dangerously codependent.
如果她说的正是泰勒呢
What if she was describing Tyler?
她可能就是因此而做了施虐女郎
Maybe that's why she became a dominatrix,
从而有勇气来为自己出头
to give her the courage to stand up for herself.
让警员仔细检查医院的安全监控录像
We have uniforms combing through hospital security footage.
只要泰勒在那天晚上任何时间离开
If Tyler left at any point that night,
那上面都应该有记录
there should be some trace.
同时  还要继续追查
In the meantime, let's just keep digging through
那些调查报告
those notebooks.
要想起诉的话
We're gonna need more than speculation
不能只靠推测
if we want to file charges.
明白
Great.
爸爸
Dad!
要解释一下吗
Do we need to talk about this?
我在调查一个案件
This is research for a case.
还有  我得给你买几双出声儿的鞋
And we need to get you some noisier shoes.
说真的  我  你加入啦啦队啦
Seriously, I-- Hey, you made the team.
没有  选拔赛还在一个月以后
No. Tryouts aren't for another month,
但阿什莉让我把她的队服带回来试穿
But Ashley let me take her uniform home
-看是否合身  -那你觉得如何呢
- to see how it fit.  - And what do you think?
我觉得这完全不是我的风格
I think it's totally not me,
所以我很喜欢
which is why I kind of like it.
-不是你的风格  所以你喜欢  -没错
- It's not you, so you like it? - Yeah.
还记得《斯道姆来临》吗
You know how in "Storm fall,"
你因为厌倦了德里克·斯道姆
you killed off Derrick Storm
而把这个角色写死了
because you were bored with him?
-记得  -有时候我也会对自己厌倦
- Yeah.  - Sometimes I feel that way about me.
我总是躲在避风港里
Like I'm hiding inside my comfort zone.
可能现在是时候冒险一下了
And maybe it's time to venture out a little.
冒险一定要包括跳啦啦操吗
Well, does that venture have to include pom-poms?
我不想以后回忆高中生活时
I don't want to look back on high school
后悔自己错过了些什么
and feel like I missed out on something.
向我保证你会支持我
So promise you'll be supportive.
好吧  我
Yeah, I, uh...
我保证
I promise.
真棒  爸爸
Go, dad!
你曾经想过要当个啦啦队员吗
You ever want to be a cheerleader?
没有  你有吗
No. Did you?
不是我  是阿丽克西斯
Not me. Alexis.
-她想进啦啦队  -那又怎样呢
- She wants to try out for the team.  - So?
怎样  你看到她们穿的什么了吗
So? You see what they wear?
她想进啦啦队
She wants to join a team,
还不如参加数学竞赛
why not join mathletes?
她为什么不能两者都参加呢
Why can't she do both?
而且  小孩子会用与试衣服相同的方法
Besides, kids try on personalities
去尝试不同的个人风格
the way they try on clothes.
这是他们了解自己的方式
It's the way that they figure out who they are.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
根据监控录像
According to the security footage,
她男朋友在值班期间没有离开过医院
the boyfriend never left the hospital during his shift.
-凶手不是他  -可能他伪造了录像
- It wasn't him.  - Maybe he faked the footage.
他只是个实习生  不是杰森·伯恩[参见电影《谍影重重》]
He's an intern, not Jason Bourne.
那么又回到人物乙的问题上来了
Oh. Well, there goes my subject "B" theory.
杰西卡7点半离开了"地牢"
So Jessica left the dungeon at 7:30,
而她在10点和11点之间被杀害
and she was killed sometime between 10:00 and 11:00.
如果她既没回家又没回学校
If she didn't go home or to the university,
那她去哪儿了呢
then where did she go?
过来看一下  有发现
Something in here you gotta see.
有一个杰西卡的研究对象
It's one of Jessica's subjects.
她称之为“我是萨姆”[苏斯博士的作品]
She calls him "Sam-I-am."
因为他痴迷苏斯博士吗[儿童读物作家]
Because he has a Dr. Seuss fetish?
SAM是缩写  全称是"聪明绝顶的受虐狂"
Because he's a sam-- "A smart-assed masochist."
根据她的笔记
According to her notes,
这个萨姆假意自己想被驯服
a SAM pretends he wants to be submissive,
但真正目的却是控制他的女主人
but what he actually wants to do is dominate his mistress,
方式是以退为进
usually with passive-aggression.
他并不主动提要求
Instead of asking for what he wants,
他设计的玩法却是让别人恼火
he makes a game out of making other people upset,
由此来惩罚别人
so they can be punished.
是吗  还有这种人
Really? There's people like that?
这种萨姆是具有危险性的
Only these SAMs can be dangerous.
有时甚至以威胁手段来激起对方的反击
Sometimes resorting to threats to provoke their response.
听听这个
Listen to this.
他说"毒液女王"就是那个
He said Mistress Venom was the one
应受惩罚的人
who needed to be punished.
他说他要找到她  把她绑起来
He said he was going to find her, tie her up
然后淹死她
and drown her,
但是是用某种
but in something...
蜜浆  如焦糖
sweet, like caramel."
性癖好  还有对犯罪现场的描写
Sexual obsession and a description of the crime scene.
听起来像是凶手
Sounds like our guy to me.
确实  但我们只有绰号
Yeah, but we only got a nickname.
我们不只有个绰号  我们完全可以
We have more than a nickname. We have enough
逼伊琳娜夫人交出她的客户名单
to force lady Irena to turn over her client list.
请帮我连线马克威法官
Judge Markway, please.
哦  看来有人要接受惩罚了
Ooh. Sounds like someone's gonna get punished.
威廉姆·卡若威  即“我是萨姆”
William Karaway, a.k.a."Sam-I-am"
高级副总裁
Senior vice president at
任职于"斯图特&卡伯特&萨根"公司
Stewart, Cabot and Sagansky.
-那个全球咨询公司  -没错
- The global consulting firm?  - Mm-hmm.
难怪伊琳娜夫人要隐瞒他的身份
No wonder lady Irena was protecting his identity.
卡塞尔  这次你就不参与审讯了吧
Castle, why don't you sit this one out?
我想面对一个强势点的女性  卡若威先生
I think Mr. Caraway will respond better to a strong...
会更加配合一点
female hand.
我是萨姆  被关在屋子里
Sam-I-am... in a box...
还有一只母老虎  我们有好戏看了
with a fox-- We're gonna need some popcorn.
坐下
Sit.
你该先告诉我为什么把我关在这儿
First why don't you tell me why the hell I'm here?
-我有个董事会  -我叫你坐下  立刻
- I got a board meeting... - I said sit down... now.
真乖
Good boy.
你的女主人将为你感到非常骄傲
Your mistress would be very proud of you.
你说什么
Excuse me?
"毒液女王"
Mistress Venom.
"伊琳娜夫人的痛苦庄园"
Lady Irena's house of pain.
你喜欢被绑  喜欢被鞭打
You like to be tied up, you like to be spanked.
但相比之下  你更喜欢威胁别人
But more than anything, you like to make threats.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
在纽约  施虐女郎的顾客是没有隐私的
There is no dominatrix-client privilege in New York.
而你的主人很详尽的记录了
And your mistress was very thorough
你内心深处最黑暗的欲望
in documenting your deepest, darkest desires--
那些配套工具  你喜欢怎样玩儿
the thing with the matches, how you liked it messy.
她都写下来啦
She wrote that down?
她也写了你如何想要反过来虐待她
She also wrote how you wanted to turn the tables on her,
你威胁要把她绑起来  在焦糖中溺死她
how you threatened to tie her up and drown her in caramel.
我  这只是幻想
I-it's fantasy.
但你不满足于幻想
But the fantasies weren't enough.
所以就让它成为了现实
And so you had to make your dreams come true.
不  这不可能
No, that's not possible.
她越抵抗  你就越痴迷
The more she said no, the more you became obsessed.
你不想做奴隶
You didn't want to be the submissive.
你想要主宰她
You wanted to dominate her,
而最终极的主宰就是谋杀
and the ultimate domination is murder.
不  我发誓  我都不知道她死了
No, I swear. I didn't even know she was dead.
你威胁她时说的具体内容
You were very specific in your threats,
和尸体被发现时完全一样
and that's exactly how we found her.
你还想否认那不是你干的
Do you really expect me to believe that that wasn't you?
肯定是有人发现了这个
Well--well, someone must have found out.
可能有人看过她的笔记
Someone could've read her notes.
前天晚上你在哪儿
Where were you two nights ago?
卡若威先生  你在哪里
Mr. Caraway, where were you?
我和我妻子在一起
I was with my wife.
那天是我们的结婚周年日
It was our anniversary.
他妻子证实了
His wife confirms it.
他整晚都和她一起在周年晚会上
He was with her at the anniversary party all night.
这个手法简直太独特了
This staging was way too specific
不可能只是个巧合  肯定有人知道内情
to be just a coincidence. Somebody knew.
可能是她告诉谁了
Maybe she told someone.
或者有人看过她的调查报告
Maybe someone had access to the research.
文件柜又不是诺克斯堡[美军事基地]
Filing cabinet's not Fort Knox.
任何可以打开文件柜的人都能看到这些记录
Anyone with access would've read exactly what we read
然后借刀杀人
and could use it to throw us off their trail.
好  你和莱恩再去一次"地牢"
Okay. You and Ryan go back to the dungeon.
看有没有哪个女郎能提供点线索
See if any of the girls swap stories after work.
同时  卡塞尔和我去学校
Meanwhile, Castle and I will go to the university
查看下谁动过她的报告
and see who had access to her research.
好
Okay.
没  "毒液女王"从未对我提到过他
No, Mistress Venom never mentioned him to me,
也没提过其他客户
or any of her other clients.
是吗  别耍我了
Really? Come on.
难道你们从不讨论客户吗
You girls don't share shop talk?
在这里工作久了之后
You work here long enough,
你能想象的最怪癖的事情
and the kinkiest things you could ever imagine...
就是明天还要再来
are just another day at the office.
客户共享时  我们才交换信息
The only time we trade info is if we share clients.
但"毒液女王"从不和我们分享
But Mistress Venom didn't share.
能帮我把靴子解开吗
Do you mind unstrapping my boot?
谢谢  "琥珀女王"
Uh, thank you, Mistress Amber?
-是的  -以及"蝎子女王"
- Yes.  - Mistress Scorpion?
好了  有点混乱  不好意思
Okay, I get 'em confused. I'm sorry.
快点
Faster.
她有没有可能会
Is, uh, is there a possibility
对一个客户说另一个客户的
that she may have mentioned one client's fetishes
-一些癖好  -绝对不可能
- to another client?  -Absolutely not.
伊琳娜夫人让我们牢记一定要保密
Lady Irena beats confidentiality rules into our heads.
"毒液女王"又不是傻瓜
Mistress Venom wasn't stupid.
有那么难解吗
Is there a problem?
这个结  像个八角结
Just this knot. It's like an octagonal knot.
像有八个角似的  我从没见过这样的结
It's got, like, eight sides. I've never seen a knot like--
埃斯波西托警探让罪行低头下跪
Detective Esposito bringing crime to its knees.
不准走
Stay.
没有哪个女郎听到杰西卡
So none of the girls claim that they remember Jessica
谈论过她的任何一位客户
talking about any of her clients.
但对于她离开这里到被杀害的
But I think we might have an explanation
那段时间  她去了哪儿
as to where she was between the time she left work
似乎找到了些答案
and when she was killed.
"蝎子女王"认为
Uh, Mistress Scorpion thinks
杰西卡可能在捞外快
that Jessica might have been working off the books.
如果是这样的话  那她就是自找麻烦
Well, if she was, then she was asking for trouble.
伊琳娜夫人最烦的就是  有些女郎
Nothing upsets lady Irena more than some girl
企图吞掉本该她赚的40%
trying to screw her out of her 40%.
爱尔兰来的  帮一下你这位小兄弟吧
Hey, Irish, you want to help out your little buddy here?
他笨手笨脚的
He seems to be all thumbs.
你和她在同一间办公室  凯莉
You were her officemate Kelly.
你要想拿到她的报告简直轻而易举
It would've been very easy for you to access her files.
不  不可能  我说过了
No, it wouldn't. I told you.
她对自己的工作非常保密
She was very private about her work.
你是说她
You mean to tell me,
从没把笔记留在桌上
she didn't once slip out to the bathroom
然后去洗手间吗
and just leave her notes sitting on the desk?
就算有  我也没兴趣
If she did, I wouldn't be interested.
而且她被杀害的那晚
And the night she was killed,
我和家人在威彻斯特
I was in Westchester with my folks.
还有别人有这个办公室的钥匙吗
Does anyone else have access to this office?
还有唯一一个有钥匙的人
The only other person with a key to the office
-就是管理员  -你的钥匙呢
- is maintenance. - What about your keys?
-有没有掉过或借给某个朋友  -没有
- Did you ever lose them or lend them to a friend?  - No.
上星期我给过马特
I mean, I gave them to Matt last week
因为他说他落了些文件在这儿了
because he said he had some papers here.
难道你觉得他撬开了她的文件柜
What, you think he broke in to her filing cabinet
然后拿了她的研究报告
and took her research?
这正是我所想的
That is exactly what I'm thinking.
你自己说过  这是个竞争性很大的研究课题
You said it yourself. It's a very competitive program.
而且他们是同一奖学金的最终候选人
And they were both finalists for the same fellowship.
这是马特研究艾滋病
This is, uh, Matt's proposal for studying
对市区门诊影响的开题报告
the effect of A.I.D.S. on inner-city clinics.
-看这张照片  -他穿着实习医生服
- Look at the picture.  - He's in scrubs.
那个在"地牢"
It wasn't Tyler who
和杰西卡对质的人不是泰勒
confronted Jessica at the dungeon.
是马特
It was matt.
我借了凯莉的钥匙  那并不能证明什么
I borrowed Kelly's keys. That doesn't prove anything.
所以我们才仔细审查了整个案件
Which is why we took a look at the whole picture.
这是从你的手机
This is a list of phone calls
打到学校总机的电话单
made from your cell phone to the university switchboard.
每一个都和杰西卡接到的骚扰电话相吻合
Each one coincides with a harassing call to Jessica.
是你打的那些电话
You made those calls.
这只是个玩笑
Look, it was a joke.
那你上星期去"地牢"找杰西卡
How about your little visit to Jessica
又作何解释呢
at the dungeon last week?
那也是个玩笑吗
Was that a joke as well?
她没告诉过任何人"地牢"的地点
She didn't tell anybody where the dungeon was.
你是如何找到的
So how'd you find it?
你是跟踪她还是根据她报告上的线索找到的
Did you follow her or the clues in her research?
你是她争取奖学金的竞争对手
You were her rival for a fellowship.
你需要除掉她
You needed her out of the way.
而当看到她的报告时  你发现了机会
And when you read her research, you saw your chance.
没错  我是需要那笔钱
Look, I needed that funding, okay?
我的研究很重要  本来就是  说实话
My work is important. I mean, come on. Seriously.
我不能让她拿到那笔奖学金
I couldn't let her get that fellowship.
我看了她的报告  写的像小说一样
And when I saw her research, I mean, it read like fiction.
于是我就到"地牢"去查看究竟
So I went to the dungeon to find out.
也就是说你撬开了她的文件柜
So you broke in to her filing cabinet,
复印了她的研究报告
you copied her research,
接着跟踪她到"地牢"
and then you followed her to the dungeon.
你可没怎么在清白那栏里
You're not putting a whole lot of checks
打勾啊  马特
in the innocent column here, Matt.
清白栏
The innocent column.
听着  我是威胁过她
Listen... I threatened her.
我认了  但我没杀她
All right? But I did not kill her.
当我发现她就是"毒液女王"后
When I found out that she was Mistress Venom,
我跟她说  如果她不撤销
I told her that if she didn't withdraw
奖学金申请  我就告诉她男友真相
her fellowship application, I was gonna tell her boyfriend.
-结果不奏效  你就杀了她  -奏效了
- And when that didn't work, you killed her?  - It did work.
杰西卡在被杀前一天撤销了申请
Jessica withdrew her application the day before she was killed.
-你如何知道  -因为她抄送给我了
- How do you know? - Because she blind copied me on an e-mail
她发给委员会主席的电邮
that she sent to the head of the committee.
我跟她没冲突了
We were cool.
她最关心的是拿回
What she was most concerned about was getting back
我复印的研究报告
this research that I copied.
她没跟我争奖学金之后
So as soon as she was out of the running,
我就送回到她的公寓了
I brought it all back to her apartment.
他知道  如果洗脱嫌疑的证据是勒索
You know you are morally challenged,
他将受到道德上的谴责
if your murder alibi is a blackmailing scheme.
是的  如果他说的是实话
Yeah, but if he's telling the truth,
我们就缺少动机
then we have no motive.
你们好  绅士们
Well, hello, gentleman.
"地牢"之行怎样
How was your trip to the dungeon?
原来埃斯波西托对鞋带不怎么在行
Well, we learned that Esposito is not very good with laces.
鞋带太多了  我替你解开的
There were a lot of lace-- I-I loosened 'em for you.
没错
Yeah, sure.
那里的人都说杰西卡
None of the girls admit to Jessica sharing
不和她们八卦客人的秘密
any of her client secrets with 'em.
有一个认为她也许在"地牢"外见客户
Oh, one of 'em thought that she might have been seeing clients
这刚好填补了时间上的缺失部分
outside of the dungeon, which might explain the hole in our timeline.
但我们再次调查她的电话和收入
But we ran through her phones and financials again.
我们却找不到任何记录
We can't find any record of it.
你们进展如何  听说有个嫌疑人
How about you? Hear you have a suspect.
曾有个  马特说的是实话
Had. Matt was telling the truth.
杰西卡退出了奖学金争夺战
Jessica pulled out of the fellowship.
但如果他说的是实话  那他送回她公寓的
But if he was telling the truth, then where's all the research
研究报告又在哪里
he brought back to her apartment?
出于隐私的考虑
Given her concerns for privacy,
她不可能扔掉
she wouldn't just throw it away.
我们知道她并没有带回大学里
And we know she didn't take it back to the university.
也许我们遗漏了某些细节
Well, maybe we missed something.
也许她把研究报告藏在某处了
Maybe she hid it somewhere.
又或许马特对研究报告的事撒了谎
Or maybe Matt is lying about the research.
你没见过一叠论文吗
So you didn't see a stack of paperwork?
没有  有的话我会注意到
No, I would've noticed that.
-也许她带回学校了  -那里也没有
- Maybe she took them up to school? - No, it wasn't there either.
你们确定马特说的是实话吗
Are you sure Matt's telling the truth?
大多数人为了不被怀疑而撒谎
Most people lie to avoid suspicion.
但很少人会撒谎让自己有罪
Not a lot of people lie to incriminate themselves.
你回到家的那天晚上
That night that you came home,
有没有留意到不同或东西放错
did you notice anything different or out of place?
说起这个  我确实发现有些奇怪
Now that you mention it, I did find something odd.
今天我收拾洗碗机时
Earlier today I was emptying the dishwasher,
我发现一个酒杯  上面沾有口红印
and I found a wine glass with lipstick on it.
看起来不像是杰西卡的
It didn't seem like Jessica's shade,
也不是我的
and it wasn't one of mine.
我放到一边  打算迟点手洗
I put it aside to hand-wash it later.
认得这颜色吗
Recognize this shade?
如果没搞错  也不可能错
If I'm not mistaken, and I rarely am,
那是"血色女王"
That's Mistress Red.
你知道吗  唇印跟指纹相似
Did you know that lip prints are a lot like fingerprints?
绝对是独一无二的
No two are exactly alike.
我们在杰西卡公寓里
We found this on a wine glass
一个酒杯上找到的
in Jessica's apartment.
当我们比对过你的嘴唇后  将有何发现
What do you think we'll find when we compare it to your lips?
-这唇印可能数月前就印上去了  -绝对不是
- That stain could've been there for months.  - But it wasn't.
我们查过用车服务
We checked with your... car service.
他们确认晚上9点把你载到
They said they dropped you off at 9:00 P.M.
杰西卡住所前  就在她被杀当晚
in front of Jessica's place the night she was killed.
你是最后一个见过她的人
You were the last one to see her alive.
那晚发生了什么
What happened that night?
你发现了她的真实身份吗
Did you find out who she really was?
她未经客户同意就对其进行研究
That she was studying her clients without their permission?
如果这泄露出去
I mean, if word of that got out...
对你生意是致命打击
that would've destroyed your business.
那会使你不高兴
That can't have made you happy.
你自以为抓了根救命稻草
And you're grasping at straws,
也没什么可高兴的
and that can't make you happy.
探长  这个时候
Detective, at this time,
我要求律师到场
I'm exercising my right to legal counsel.
我不会再回答任何问题
I won't be answering any further questions.
对伊琳娜夫人的审问如何
How'd it go with lady Irena?
她摆出律师的架势
She's lawyering up.
你们在杰西卡公寓有何发现
What'd you guys find at Jessica's apartment?
我们好像找到了罪案现场
Well, it looks like we found the crime scene.
伊琳娜对善后工作相当在行
Irena was pretty good at cleaning up after herself.
没有打斗痕迹  没有血迹
There was no trace or blood evidence,
但杰西卡的床头柜附近
but the area around Jessica's bedside table
火花曾像圣诞树那样耀眼
lit up like a christmas tree.
地板还用漂白剂擦洗过
It'd been scrubbed down with bleach.
难怪我们找不到杰西卡的研究报告
That's why we didn't find Jessica's research.
伊琳娜处理掉了一切证据
Irena got rid of it all.
没错  但她并未处理干净
Yeah, but she didn't quite clean everything.
鉴证组把床罩等清空进行取样化验
Once C.S.U. stripped the bed, the swab test
结果表明一个枕头上留有
revealed dried saliva in one of her pillows
她被窒息时尖叫所留下的唾液
from her screams as she was smothered.
看来她是不择手段地保护生意
Looks like she'd do anything to protect her business,
杀人也在所不惜
even kill.
管她是不是律师  逮捕她
All right, lawyer or not, let's book her.
行动
Let's do it.
你在滤水  还是考验我的耐心
Are you straining those noodles or just my patience?
抱歉  只是
Oh, I'm... sorry. Just...
这个案子
Hmm. This case.
我一直在想出了什么纰漏
I keep thinking that I'm missing something.
我也是  忘了放盐
Yeah, me, too. Salt.
这会钠中毒的
Can you die from sodium poisoning?
有道理
Ooh. You have a point.
闻起来不错
Hey, that smells good.
但我吃过了
But... I already ate?
不是吧
Oh, no.
你和阿什莉进行了啦啦队排练吗
So did you and Ashley do cheerleading practice?
没有  没想到
Uh, no. Turns out,
啦啦队和我的击剑课
cheerleading conflicts with my fencing schedule,
小提琴课还有法语俱乐部撞车了
my violin lessons and french club.
啦啦队更像一种生活方式
Cheerleading is more of a lifestyle.
我可以看个热闹
And as much as I like to visit,
却不一定要参与
it's not really a place I'd like to live.
我说过她会自己想通的
I told you she'd figure it out.
今天我们都上了宝贵一课
Well, we both learned a valuable lesson today.
你知道自己可以开阔眼界和成长
You learned that you can expand your horizons and grow.
而我知道了如果涉及超短裙和男生
I learned that if that involves short skirts and boys,
-我不会喜欢的  -明白
- I'm not gonna like it.  - Fair enough.
很好  你们都吸取了教训
Fine. Now that you've both learned your lessons,
开始洗碗如何
how about starting on the dishes?
你需要一个消防大水管才能洗干净
You're gonna need a fire hose to clean this up.
不  我做饭  你收拾
No, I cooked. Someone else cleans up.
收拾
Clean up.
-谁洗了枕套  -什么
- Who washed the pillowcase?  - What?
埃斯波西托说鉴证组在把床罩等清空
Esposito said C.S.U. didn't find anything
取样前是一无所获
until they stripped the bed.
也就是说枕头上有唾液
That means there was saliva on the pillow,
但枕套上却没有
but not on the pillowcase.
没错  有人清洗了枕套
You're right. Someone washed the pillowcase.
但清洗烘干至少要1小时
But the washer-dryer cycle would've taken at least an hour.
这样的话  她室友必然回家了
At which point, the roommate would've been home.
伊琳娜不可能及时逃离现场
Irena couldn't have gotten out in time.
只有一个人可以把公寓收拾干净
Only one person could've cleaned the apartment.
我不明白
I-I don't understand.
我以为你们已经抓到凶手
I thought you'd caught the killer.
我们也以为是
We thought so, too.
若不是她  又会是谁
If it wasn't her, then who?
是你  丹妮尔
It was you, Danielle.
我
Me?
我为什么要杀害最好的朋友
Oh, why would I kill my best friend?
在她的研究中
In her research,
杰西卡写道自己身处不正常的恋情中
Jessica describes being in a dysfunctional relationship.
她不敢离去
One she was scared to leave
因为对方施以危险性纠缠
because the other person had become so dangerously codependent.
我们最初以为是她男友泰勒
At first we thought it was her boyfriend Tyler.
但其实不是
But it wasn't, was it?
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
马特放下的研究报告  她的研究报告
The research that Matt dropped off--her research--
她对你的描写
Must've been very hurtful
读来必定让人伤心欲绝
to read all the things that she wrote about you.
杰西卡爱我  她绝不会伤害我
Jessica loved me. She would never hurt me.
人物乙显示了性受虐狂的一切症状
"Subject 'b' shows all the signs of being a masochist,
完全依赖其自我感觉
completely dependent for her sense of self."
我们知道你读了那些资料  丹妮尔
We know you read the files, Danielle.
所以你才那样处置她的尸体
That's why you staged her body that way.
不  我没有看  这里没什么资料
No, I didn't read anything. There was nothing here.
因为你把一切都烧掉了
Because you got rid of it all.
-你错了  -就是你  丹妮尔
- You're wrong.  - It had to have been you, Danielle.
你是唯一有时间清理现场的人
You were the only one who had time to clean up after yourself.
从她的办公地方判断  杰西卡不是那种
Judging from her office space, Jessica wasn't the kind of girl
会用漂白剂擦地的人
that scrubbed her floor clean with bleach.
杰西卡告诉你  她必须离开你
Jessica told you... she had to get away from you.
她告诉你  她要离开
She told you... she was gonna leave.
她
She...
她是我的一切
She was... everything to me.
我以为我们是家人
I thought we were family.
但她写了那些可怕的文字
But then she wrote those awful things!
她没有权利
She had no right.
那天晚上发生了什么
What happened that night?
她说她要搬出去
She said she was... gonna move out,
她和我再无瓜葛
that she was done with me.
我推了她
I pushed her.
她跌倒了
She fell.
头部撞到桌子
Her head... hit the table.
她开始尖叫
She started to scream.
她说  她恨我
She said--she said she hated me!
我叫她闭嘴  我只是想让她闭嘴
I told her to shut up! I just wanted her to shut up.
然后你把枕头压在她头上
And then you put a pillow over her head
使她窒息而亡
and you suffocated her.
我不是有意要杀她的
I... I didn't mean to kill her.
我只是不想让她走
I just didn't want her to go.
最终  卡塞尔是对的
In the end, Castle was right.
这宗谋杀案是冲动犯罪
The murder was a crime of passion.
手铐  焦糖都是烟雾弹
The cuffs, the caramel were all just theater to throw us off.
我不禁在想
I can't help but think
如果马特没有复印杰西卡的研究报告
that if Matt hadn't copied Jessica's research,
丹妮尔也永远不会看到
Danielle never would've read it,
这一切都不会发生
none of this woulda happened.
马特现在是奖学金和学位都泡汤了
Well, now he won't get his precious little fellowship or his degree.
伊琳娜夫人呢  她去公寓里干什么
What about Lady Irena? What was she doing at the apartment?
有些女郎认为杰西卡捞外快
Some of the girls thought that Jessica was working off the books.
伊琳娜过去叫她停止
So Irena came by to tell her to knock it off.
她们喝了杯红酒  她就离开了
They had a glass of wine, and she left.
她只是没挑对时间去
She just did it on the wrong night.
没错  但她为何为难你呢
Yeah, but why'd she give you such a hard time, then?
因为她是律师
Because she's a lawyer.
还是位"女王"
And a dominatrix.
嘿  你来了
Hey. You made it.
伙计们  介绍下
Guys, uh, I want you to meet...
珍妮
Jenny.
你好
Hi.
欢迎  久闻你的大名
Welcome. We've heard wonderful things about you.
我也久闻你们的大名
Oh, the same goes for all of you.
我感觉已经认识你们很久了
I-I feel like I know you guys already.
你真人比登上《时尚》的那张照片漂亮多了
You are so much prettier than your picture in "Cosmo."
凯文给我看了《希特热浪》
Kevin gave me his copy of "Heat wave",
让我爱不释手
I could not put it down.
谢谢你这位好搭档
And thanks for being such a great partner.
要确保他办案时的安全哦
You know, make sure you keep him safe out there.
我保证
You got it.
我们要去看电影
We have a movie to catch.
明天见
I'll see you guys tomorrow.
玩的开心点
You guys have a great time.
若我有这样的女友  可能也甘心挨她两鞭子
Damn. If I had a girl like that, I might be whipped by her, too.
现在知道为何莱恩不早点带她来了吧
Now we know why he didn't bring her around sooner.
你们两个不会像傻子一样围着她转
So the two of you don't act like idiots around her.
不对  是我们不会挖他墙角
No, so we wouldn't try to steal her from him.
你那位幻想情人呢
So what about this imaginary boyfriend of yours?
我们会在这里见到他
Are we gonna see him around here
还是他在家被绑在床上亮相
or is he at home tied to a bed?
里奇  你怎么了  吃醋了
What's the matter, Ricky? You jealous?
没有  你今晚要好好惩罚他
No. You only get to punish him at night.
-你惩罚了我一整天  -你活该
- You punish me all day.  - Well, you deserve it.
-我对你干了什么  -让我们从
- What did I do to you?  - Let's just start...
初次见面说起
be first day we met.